<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mirza Waleed</title>
    <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mirza Waleed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://waleedgeo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/about.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/about.html</guid>
      <description>Mirza Waleed 🙂 PhD student (Geography) at the Department of Geography, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong (SAR).
My research interest includes: Geographic Information Science (GIS), Remote Sensing, and Environmental Modeling. More specifically, I am interested in applying geospatial techniques, machine learning, and cloud computing (e.g., Google Earth Engine) in Hazards-Risk assessment, Environmental Change Monitoring, Floods Mapping &amp;amp; Automation, Land-use science, UTFVI (Urban Heat Island effect), and climate change.
Besides, I&amp;rsquo;m a (5 star rated &amp;amp; Level-1) freelancer at Fiverr and provides Google Earth Engine based consultancy services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/blogs/blog_01_academic_website.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/blogs/blog_01_academic_website.html</guid>
      <description>How to ceate your website using Hugo &amp;amp; Github Pages by Mirza Waleed (24-08-2022)
In this post, I will share how I made My Portfolio/Bloging Website using Github Pages and Hugo.
Originally, i get inspired from this twitter thread and started preparing my website from scratch.
For better understanding of whole process install following:
Install VS Code Installl Hugo Create a Github account Install github extension in VS code and login to your github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/projects/proj_02_utfvi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/projects/proj_02_utfvi.html</guid>
      <description>Under progress&amp;hellip; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/publications.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/publications.html</guid>
      <description>Current Working Papers Earth observation for Flood Risk Assessment (Ongoing - 2022)
Multi-Temporal Resilience Evaluation in Pakistan (Ongoing - 2022)
Warming Cities in Pakistan: Evaluating Spatial-temporal Dynamics of Urban Thermal Field Variance Index under Rapid Urbanization (Ongoing - 2022)
Submitted Papers Exploring and Predicting Thermal Field Variance in Response to Urban Growth: A Geo-information Modelling-based Spatial-temporal Assessment in the Context of Sustainable and Livable Cities (Submitted as First Author, 2022 - Egyptian Journal of Remote Sensing &amp;amp; Space Science)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
