<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mirza Waleed</title>
    <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mirza Waleed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://waleedgeo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/about.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/about.html</guid>
      <description>Mirza Waleed 🙂 PhD student (Geography) at the Department of Geography, Hong Kong Baptist University , Hong Kong (SAR).
I am currently enrolled in a fully funded PhD position at HKBU, HK. I completed my bachelor in Environmental Sciences from COMSATS University Islamabad with Remote Sensing and GIS as my major and received an A+ grade in my final year research project and thesis.
I have been working in the Remote Sensing domain for the last five years focusing on Google Earth Engine, Geospatial Data Science, and Machine/Deep Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/achievements.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/achievements.html</guid>
      <description>2023 Co-authored Paper published in Applied Geography
2022 Participated in Geography Day 2022 event at the University of Hong Kong, and got 2nd Runner-Up position in oral presentation.
Got PhD fully funded 4 years PhD scholarship for PhD in Geography at the Department of Geography, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong (SAR).
Duration: 2022-2026 Funding: ~855,000 HK$ Topic: Cloud computing, Mahine Learning, and AI for Disaster Management 2021 Graduated in Environmental Sciences from COMSATS University Islamabad VHR-PK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/projects.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/projects.html</guid>
      <description>Current Working Papers A Review on Cloud computing applications in disaster risk assessment (Ongoing - 2022-23)
Earth observation for Flood Risk Assessment (Ongoing - 2022-23)
Multi-Temporal Resilience Evaluation in Pakistan (Ongoing - 2022)
Submitted Papers Warming Cities in Pakistan: Evaluating Spatial-temporal Dynamics of Urban Thermal Field Variance Index under Rapid Urbanization (Book Chapter in Springer - 2022)
Exploring and Predicting Thermal Field Variance in Response to Urban Growth: A Geo-information Modelling-based Spatial-temporal Assessment in the Context of Sustainable and Livable Cities (Submitted as First Author, 2022 - Sustainability)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://waleedgeo.github.io/publications.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waleedgeo.github.io/publications.html</guid>
      <description>Ongoing and Submitted work Published 2023 Shafi A., Chen S., Waleed M., and Sajjad M. (2023). Leveraging machine learning and remote sensing to monitor long-term spatial-temporal wetland changes: Towards a national RAMSAR inventory in Pakistan, Applied Geography, Volume 151, 2023, 102868, ISSN 0143-6228. DOI - PDF 2022 Waleed, M., Mubeen, M., Ahmad, A., Habib-ur-Rahman, M., Amin, A., Farid, H. U., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; El Sabagh, A. (2022). Evaluating the efficiency of coarser to finer resolution multispectral satellites in mapping paddy rice fields using GEE implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
